Guide to the Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis Papers
The Lewis Walpole Library
- Writings, 1915–1980; Series III; 18.56; 38 boxes
  The series holds material related to Wilmarth Lewis's many publications as well as those he never published. Within the three subseries are autograph and typed manuscripts in draft and final versions, correspondence with publishers, editors, printers, and designers, galleys, proof pages, and some artwork for dust jackets and covers.
  All of Lewis's writings are not represented here, and some that are present do not have complete documentation, but an effort was made to identify materials related to particular projects and file those together. Like many authors, particularly those who are regularly invited to give public presentations, Lewis repurposed topics and his writings on those topics—most especially the topic of Horace Walpole—and would change the title of the work. In addition, his final publication effort, "Fugitive Pieces" (Boxes 222-223), pulled together a number of his shorter writings which were retyped and edited.
  The project with the most documentation is Lewis's 1967 autobiography One Man's Education (Boxes 225-231), but the series also holds minor writings ranging from short stories and essays from his college days to a 1941 editorial published in the New York Times, to The Tadpole, a play he co-wrote with his friend and Farmington neighbor Winchell Smith; it ran briefly in 1931 at theaters in Queens and Hartford.
  - Books
    Arranged in alphabetical order by title, including unpublished works.
    - The Castle of Otranto (London: Oxford University Press, 1964), 1964, undated (Box 221, Folder 1)
    - A Catalogue of Horace Walpole's Library (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1969), 1967–1969 (Box 221, Folder 2-3)
      Present are correspondence, drafts and galley copy of Lewis's preface, dust jacket design, mailing lists, and other notes.
    - Collector's Progress (New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1951), 1941–1963 (Box 221, Folder 4-5)
      Correspondence with Blanche and Alfred A. Knopf, and other staff members at the publishing house.
    - "Fugitive Pieces": Set One
      Lewis wrote that "Fugitive Pieces" was meant to be a one-volume compilation of "fifty-two pieces I wrote from 1932 to 1978." They include short essays and academic papers, and speeches delivered by him at libraries, museums, clubs, conferences, memorial services, and various other gatherings. He worked on the manuscript in the last year of his life, arranging and editing earlier writings. He had submitted it to colleagues for criticism and to Yale University Press for publication estimates, but in 1980 the press declined to move forward with the project until after the final volumes of the Walpole correspondence series were issued.
      Set one has original typescripts, edited.
      - Notes and estimates, 1978–1980 (Box 222, Folder 1)
      - Preliminaries and introduction, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 2)
      - I. The Public Life of a Private Library, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 3)
      - II. Collectors, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 4)
      - III. Libraries, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 5)
      - IV. Museums and a Dedication, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 6)
      - V. Horace Walpole, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 7)
      - VI. The Correspondence of Horace Walpole, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 8)
      - VII. The Eighteenth Century, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 9)
      - VIII. An Anniversary and a Commencement, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 10)
      - IX. Friends, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 11)
      - X. A Lunch with Max Beerbohm, Rapallo, 1954, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 12)
      - XI. Dodsley's Collection, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 13)
      - XII. Trustees and Presidents, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 14)
      - XIII. Doubting Thomas: a Layman's Sermon, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 15)
      - XIV. Monday Evening Club, 1978–1979 (Box 222, Folder 16)
      - Postscript, 1979 (Box 222, Folder 17)
    - "Fugitive Pieces": Set Two
      Set Two is a carbon copy of set one, kept by Lewis's librarian Catherine Jestin and with her annotations and notes, as well as her file on editing and her set of annotated catalogue cards describing Lewis's writings. Otherwise, the arrangement follows the same sequence as Set One.
      - Notes on selection, arrangement, and editing, 1973–1980 (Box 223, Folder 1)
      - Card files, undated (Box 223, Folder 2)
      - Preliminaries and introduction, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 3)
      - I. The Public Life of a Private Library, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 4)
      - II. Collectors, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 5)
      - III. Libraries, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 6)
      - IV. Museums and a Dedication, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 7)
      - V. Horace Walpole, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 8)
      - VI. The Correspondence of Horace Walpole, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 9)
      - VII. The Eighteenth Century, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 10)
      - VIII. An Anniversary and a Commencement, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 11)
      - IX. Friends, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 12)
      - X. A Lunch with Max Beerbohm, Rapallo, 1954, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 13)
      - XI. Dodsley's Collection, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 14)
      - XII. Trustees and Presidents, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 15)
      - XIII. Doubting Thomas: a Layman's Sermon, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 16)
      - XIV. Monday Evening Club, 1978–1979 (Box 223, Folder 17)
      - Postscript, 1979 (Box 223, Folder 18)
    - Horace Walpole (New York: Pantheon Books, 1960)
      The A. W. Mellon Lectures in the Fine Arts were delivered at the National Gallery, Washington, in 1960, and published in three editions by Pantheon Books under its Bollingen series. Prior to Washington, Lewis worked through his presentations with friends in New Haven, and the files hold commentary from Herman ("Fritz") Liebert, Carl and Margaret Rollins, and Thornton Wilder.
      - Correspondence, 1958–1963 (Box 224, Folder 1-2)
      - Correspondence with WGBH regarding taping of lectures, 1960 (Box 224, Folder 3)
      - Typescripts, corrected, 1958–1959 (Box 224, Folder 4-8)
      - Typescripts, corrected, 1958–1959 (Box 225, Folder 1-2)
    - "A Layman and Libraries", 1952 (Box 225, Folder 3)
      Parts of a proposed "second of three books on books. The first was Collector's Progress ."
    - One Man's Education (New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1967)
      - Correspondence, 1965–1977 (Box 225, Folder 4-6)
        Primarily correspondence with Alfred A. Knopf and staff of the publishing house concerning editing and production; also present are sketches and designs for the book cover and dust jacket. Later correspondence covers royalties and Lewis's search for copies of the book.
      - Research notes, 1961-1964, undated (Box 225, Folder 7)
      - Introduction and illustrations, 1965–1966 (Box 225, Folder 8)
      - Chapters I - VI (Box 226, Folder 1-7)
      - Chapters VII - XIII (Box 227, Folder 1-7)
      - Chapters XIV - XIX (Box 228, Folder 1-7)
      - Chapters XIX - XXV (Box 229, Folder 1-9)
      - Chapters XXVI - XXXIII (Box 230, Folder 1-9)
      - Chapters XXXIV - XXXV (Box 231, Folder 1-2)
      - Miscellaneous pages (Box 231, Folder 3)
      - Reader comments and corrections, 1961–1968 (Box 231, Folder 4)
      - Illustrations and plate proofs, 1967, undated (Box 231, Folder 5)
      - Blank book sample from Kingsport Press, 1967 (Box 231, Folder 6)
    - Private Charity in England, 1747-1757 (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1938)
      By W. S. Lewis and Ralph M. Williams, with the assistance of John M. Webb and A. Stuart Daley
      - Bound typescript, 1938 (Box 232, Folder 1)
        Inscribed on flyleaf: "To Mr. W. S. Lewis / With the affectionate regard / of his first class in History 155. / December 25, 1938
      - Typescript, corrected and marked for typesetting, with corrected galley of chapter III, 1938 (Box 232, Folder 2)
        Gift of Yale University Press, 1954.
    - Read as You Please (Cleveland: The Rowfant Club, 1977)
      A series of essays written at different points in Lewis's life, and gathered for publication by the Rowfant Club.
      - I. Goneril's Husband, undated (Box 233, Folder 1)
      - II. The Young Waterman, undated (Box 233, Folder 2)
      - III. A House Party at Stowe, undated (Box 233, Folder 3)
      - IV. Rosencrantz and Guildenstern, undated (Box 233, Folder 4)
      - VI. The Old Testament Apocrypha, undated (Box 233, Folder 5)
      - VII. The Sharp Contention Between St. Paul and St. Barnabas, undated (Box 233, Folder 6)
      - VIII. The New Testament Apocrypha, undated (Box 233, Folder 7)
      - IX. War and Peace, undated (Box 233, Folder 8)
      - X. Cicero and Old Age, undated (Box 233, Folder 9)
      - Copy sent to W. Powell-Jones, 19 July 1976 (Box 233, Folder 10)
      - Copy checked - OK - 20 July 1976 (Box 233, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous notes and edits, undated (Box 233, Folder 12)
    - Rescuing Horace Walpole (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1978)
      - Concept notes and correspondence, 1975–1978 (Box 234, Folder 1)
      - Illustration lists, 1978 (Box 234, Folder 2)
      - Edits and corrections, 1977–1980 (Box 234, Folder 3)
      - The Fantasy, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 4)
      - 1. "Short Notes", 1977 (Box 234, Folder 5)
      - 2. Sir Robert and Lady Walpole by Eccardt, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 6)
      - 3. The Ladies Waldegrave, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 7)
      - 4. Walpole's notebooks, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 8)
      - 5. Bentley's drawings for Strawberry Hill, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 9)
      - 6. Bentley's designs for Gray's Poems, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 10)
      - 7. The Journal and Printing Office, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 11)
      - 8. and 9. Walpole's Description of Strawberry Hill, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 12)
      - 10. Walpole's copy of Anecdotes of Painting in England, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 13)
      - 11. Beauclerk's drawings for The Mysterious Mother, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 14)
      - 12. Lysons, Environs of London, 1977 (Box 234, Folder 15)
      - 13. "Tracts of the Reign of George 3", 1977 (Box 235, Folder 1)
      - 14. Walpole's Chattertoniana, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 2)
      - 15. Walpole's transcripts of letters to Mann, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 3)
      - 16. Tonton's snuff-box, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 4)
      - 17. Walpole's last letter to Lady Ossory, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 5)
      - 18. Mary Berry's sketch book, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 6)
      - 19. Cole's Copy of The Castle of Otranto, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 7)
      - 20. Walpole's Richard III portfolio, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 8)
      - 21. Manuscript of Walpole's 1769 journal, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 9)
      - 22. Gordon at Newgate by Newton, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 10)
      - 23. Hogarth's oil sketch for The Beggar's Opera, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 11)
      - 24. and 25. Ramsay's portrait of Walpole, Berwick's of Conway, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 12)
      - 26. Walpole's annotated portrait print by Reynolds, 1977 (Box 235, Folder 13)
    - See For Yourself (New York: Harper & Row, 1971), 1969–1976
      Lewis hoped that Alfred A. Knopf would publish the volume; see Knopf's file in Series I, Box 75, folders 3-4, for correspondence and reader reports concerning the project.
      - Correspondence and contract, 1969–1972 (Box 236, Folder 1-2)
      - Introduction, undated (Box 236, Folder 3)
      - Essays: Memling through Sargent, 1968–1969 (Box 236, Folder 4-7)
      - Essay: Earl, 1968–1969 (Box 237, Folder 1-2)
      - Postscript, undated (Box 237, Folder 3)
      - Illustrations, undated (Box 237, Folder 4-5)
      - Clippings, 1970–1975 (Box 237, Folder 6)
    - Selected Letters of Horace Walpole (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1973), 1972–1973 (Box 237, Folder 7-9)
    - Three Tours Through London (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1941), 1940–1941 (Box 238, Folder 1-2)
      Delivered as the Charles K. Colver Lectures at Brown University.
    - Tutors' Lane (New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1922), 1919–1922 (Box 238, Folder 3-6)
      Typescript, mounted proof sheets, and galley proofs, corrected. Also present is a 1919 autograph letter, signed, from Sara Elizabeth Parsons (1864-1949).
    - The Yale Collections (New Haven: Yale University Press, 1946), 1940–1946 (Box 238, Folder 7)
      Published as part of a postwar celebration of the arts; see also Series II, Box 215, folder 2.
  - Speeches and Lectures
    The material in this subseries was kept together in a series of files grouped as "Speeches and Essays." Some venues and occasions were only identified by file title, such as "Freshmen 19 Dec. 1939" or "Moore, Fanny 14 Dec. 1965," with no other context; when possible, additional information was gleaned from Lewis's daybooks.
    The files hold autograph notes and outlines, drafts and completed texts, correspondence, and publicity material such as invitations, tickets, press releases, and newspaper clippings. Some files also have offprints and other published texts that were subsequently issued. Dates given at the folder level are those of the events and do not reflect the span of material within the folder.
    Also included here are transcripts of Lewis's appearance on the "Yale Reports" radio program (Box 247, Folder 18.)
    Organized by venue, and chronologically thereunder.
    - American Historical Association, 1954 December 30 (Box 239, Folder 1)
      Session on "Publishing the Papers of Great Men"
    - American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1941 May 5 (Box 239, Folder 2)
      Remarks on Carol Purington Rollins
    - American Law Institute, 1963 May 24 (Box 239, Folder 3)
      Address at annual dinner
    - American Philosophical Society, 1956 January 16 (Box 239, Folder 4)
      Acceptance speech on behalf of Yale University
    - American Philosophical Society, 1963 April 19 (Box 239, Folder 5)
      Address at dinner; published as "Editing Private Correspondence" in Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society 107, no. 4 (1963)
    - Art Gallery of Toronto, 1957 November 6 (Box 239, Folder 6)
      "Horace Walpole's Portraits"
    - Australian Broadcasting Corporation, 1947 March 16 (Box 239, Folder 7)
      Remarks on searching for Walpole letters.
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1952–1956 (Box 239, Folder 8)
    - Brooks School, 1948 June 12 (Box 239, Folder 9)
      Prize Day address.
    - Bucknell University, 1958 September 17 (Box 239, Folder 10)
      "Editing Private Letters," evening lecture following commencement.
    - Century Association, New York, 1969 February 6 (Box 239, Folder 11)
      Remarks at monthly meeting
    - The Club, Farmington
      - "The Young Waterman", 1974 April 3 (Box 239, Folder 12)
        Published in Read as You Please (Cleveland: The Rowfant Club, 1977).
      - [On serendipity in his life], 1974 November 21 (Box 239, Folder 13)
    - Club of Odd Volumes, Boston, 1969 May 21 (Box 239, Folder 14)
    - Columbia Broadcasting System, New York, 1955 May (Box 239, Folder 15)
      Interview on "Invitation to Learning" show
    - Columbia University, 1954 November 10 (Box 239, Folder 16)
      Remarks to English Graduate Union
    - Conference of Eastern College Librarians, 1939 November 25 (Box 239, Folder 17)
    - Farmington Historical Society, 1976 July 4 (Box 240, Folder 1-5)
      Remarks on the American Bicentennial; includes Lewis's research notes and correspondence regarding publication of his speech.
    - Farmington Village Library, 1953 March 7 (Box 240, Folder 6)
    - Graduates Club, New Haven, 1954 October 19 (Box 240, Folder 7)
    - Grolier Club
      - Annual meeting address, 1954 January 28 (Box 240, Folder 8)
      - Remarks at Old Book Table, 1964 October 2 (Box 240, Folder 9)
    - Harvard University, 1952 (Box 240, Folder 10)
      Phi Beta Kappa Oration, published as "Trustee and University" in Harvard Alumni Bulletin (July 5, 1952); and as "The Trustees of the Privately Endowed University," in The American Scholar 22, no. 1 (1952-53)
    - Harvard-Yale Corporation, 1960 November 18 (Box 241, Folder 1)
      Dinner remarks.
    - Henry Francis du Pont Winterthur Museum, 1969 May 12 (Box 241, Folder 2-3)
      Remarks, "The Museum and Its Library," at dedication of the Louise du Pont Crowninshield Research Building.
    - Heritage Foundation (Deerfield, Mass.), 1967 August 23 (Box 241, Folder 4)
      Commencement address.
    - Hill-Stead Museum, Farmington, 1968 June 6 (Box 241, Folder 5)
      Remarks on Farmington forty years ago.
    - Hotchkiss School, Lakeville, CT, 1940 (Box 241, Folder 6)
      Commencement address
    - Institute for Advanced Study (Princeton, N.J.), 1951 November 20 (Box 241, Folder 7)
      Remarks at opening of the Institute's library.
    - John Carter Brown Library
      - Remarks at founding of library associates, 1944 January 10 (Box 241, Folder 8)
      - Remarks at library associates twenty-fifth annual meeting, 1968 April 5 (Box 241, Folder 9)
      - Remarks at John Nicholas Brown birthday event, 1970 February 21 (Box 241, Folder 10)
    - Johnsonians, Somerville, New Jersey, 1967–1970 (Box 241, Folder 11)
      Lewis's paper, "The Accords and Resemblances of Johnson and Walpole," was privately printed for distribution by the Johnsonians (1967), then published in Bulletin of the Rocky Mountain Modern Language Association 22, no. 2 (June 1968), and in Eighteenth-Century Studies in Honor of Donald F. Hyde (New York: Grolier Club, 1970).
    - Johnsonians, Somerville, New Jersey, 1967–1970 (Box 242, Folder 1)
      Offprints of the paper.
    - Kingsley Trust Association, New Haven, 1946, 1963 (Box 242, Folder 2)
    - Kingswood School, West Hartford, 1962 June 8 (Box 242, Folder 3)
    - Library of Congress, 1952 May 1 (Box 242, Folder 4)
      Commemoration of the Newington public library's 200th anniversary.
    - Lucy Robbins Welles Library, 1952 (Box 242, Folder 5)
    - Massachusetts Historical Society, 1980 May 8 (Box 242, Folder 6)
      Paper read at annual meeting by corresponding secretary Andrew Oliver; published as "Horace Walpole, Collector" in Proceedings of the Massachusetts Historical Society 92 (1980)
    - Miss Porter's School (Farmington, Conn.), 1956–1976 (Box 242, Folder 7)
      Various short addresses
    - Modern Language Association
      - "Proposals for a New Edition of the Correspondence of Horace Walpole", 1932 December 29 (Box 242, Folder 8)
      - Presentation on editing eighteenth-century correspondence, 1937 December 28 (Box 242, Folder 9)
    - Monday Evening Club (Hartford, Conn.)
      - "What is the Most Significant Development Since 1895?", 1952 June 7 (Box 242, Folder 10)
      - "Some Notes on Museum Directors and Trustees", 1955 January 12 (Box 242, Folder 11)
        A version was later published in In Honour of Daryl Lindsay: Essays and Studies, edited by Franz Philipp and June Stewart (Melbourne: Oxford University Press, 1964); offprints are filed here.
      - "What is 'Education'?", 1960 November 14 (Box 242, Folder 12)
      - "Travel for the Aging", 1962 November 12 (Box 242, Folder 13)
        Submitted to Harper's Magazine for publication
      - "Our National Gallery", 1967 May 1 (Box 242, Folder 14)
      - "See for Yourself", 1969 December 12 (Box 242, Folder 15)
      - "War and Peace", 1975 November 3 (Box 242, Folder 16)
      - "Lord George Gordon at Newgate by Richard Newton", 1978 January 9 (Box 242, Folder 17)
      - "The Best English Verse, Trained Nurses, and the New Dark Ages", 1979 November 5 (Box 242, Folder 18)
        The paper was prepared by Lewis before his death on October 7, 1979, and read at the club's dinner meeting by John C. Parsons.
    - Mount Vernon, 1964 October 24 (Box 243, Folder 1)
    - National Gallery of Victoria, 1972 August 24 (Box 243, Folder 2)
      Address to the National Gallery Society in Melbourne, on Constable's Wivenhoe Park; published in See For Yourself (New York: Harper & Row, 1971).
    - New Haven Colony Historical Society, 1971 March 15 (Box 243, Folder 3)
    - New York Public Library, 1956 November 15 (Box 243, Folder 4)
      Address to the Women's Council
    - Papers of Benjamin Franklin, 1959 November 22 (Box 243, Folder 5)
      Remarks at dinner to celebrate volume 1
    - Pembroke College (University of Cambridge), 1971 May 7 (Box 243, Folder 6-9)
      The college's R. A. Neil Lecture; Lewis spoke on the poet Thomas Gray.
    - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1949 April 4 (Box 243, Folder 10)
    - Pierpont Morgan Library Thursday Evening Club, 1955 February 3 (Box 243, Folder 11)
    - Pocumtuck Valley Memorial Association, 1970 May 22 (Box 244, Folder 1-2)
      Remarks at centennial and library dedication
    - Princeton University. Library
      - Remarks at Strawberry Hill Press exhibition, 1933 (Box 244, Folder 3)
      - Donald F. Hyde Award, 1968 May 24 (Box 244, Folder 4)
    - Redwood Library and Athenaeum, 1947 September 4 (Box 244, Folder 5)
      Remarks commemorating the 200th anniversary of the library.
    - Rice University, Friends of Fondren Library, 1973 March 2 (Box 244, Folder 6)
      Printed in The Flyleaf 23, no. 2 (May 1973)
    - Rowfant Club (Cleveland, Ohio), 1972 December 8 (Box 244, Folder 7)
    - St. Mary's College (Twickenham, London, England), 1968 May 2 (Box 244, Folder 8)
      Paper on "Horace Walpole and his Library"
    - Smith College
      - "Horace Walpole's Library", 1947 January 17 (Box 244, Folder 9)
        Paper presented at Eighteenth Century Conference in honor of Professor D. Nichol Smith; published in The Library: The Transactions of the Bibliographical Society s5-II, issue 1 (June 1, 1947).
      - "The Difficult Art of Biography", 1954 February 22 (Box 244, Folder 10)
        Paper presented at the George Washington birthday commemoration; published in The Yale Review 44, no. 1 (September 1954).
      - William Allan Neilson Library Lecture, 1962 October 31 (Box 245, Folder 1)
    - Society of Colonial Wars in the State of Connecticut, 1970 May 6 (Box 245, Folder 2)
      Remarks on the National Portrait Gallery delivered at General Court.
    - State Library of New South Wales
      Address given at Mitchell Library, Sydney, Australia and published in The Australian Quarterly 19, no. 2 (June 1947).
      - "The Layman and Libraries", 1947 March 4 (Box 245, Folder 3)
      - "The Layman and Libraries" reprints, 1947–1956 (Box 245, Folder 4)
        The address was also published in The Yale Review 26, (Spring 1947), and then reprinted by the Friends of the Huntington Library (1947), Washington University Libraries (1947), Library Journal (1954), and Friends of the Dartmouth Library (1956).
    - Tavern Club, 1972 October 2 (Box 245, Folder 5)
    - Thacher School
      - Address at the school's semi-centenary celebration, 1939 March 20 (Box 245, Folder 6)
      - "Goneril's Husband", 1967 April (Box 245, Folder 7)
        Notes for a talk.
      - Baccalaureate address, 1978 June 3 (Box 245, Folder 8)
    - Twentieth Century Club, Hartford, 1975 April 24 (Box 245, Folder 9)
    - Trinity College, Hartford
      - Francis Goodwin II Fellowship Fund concert, 1965 May 22 (Box 245, Folder 10)
      - First annual Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis Lecture, 1974 November 14 (Box 245, Folder 11)
        "A House-Party at Stowe"; published in Lewis's Read As You Please (Cleveland: The Rowfant Club, 1977) and in The Dress of Words, ed. Robert B. White Jr. (Lawrence: University of Kansas Libraries, 1978).
      - Watkinson Library twenty-fifth Anniversary, 1977 September 20 (Box 246, Folder 1)
        "The Future of the Watkinson Library."
    - University of Cambridge, 1957 May (Box 246, Folder 2)
      Sandars Lectures delivered at Cambridge. May 7-9, 1957.
    - University of Chicago, 1962 April 9 (Box 246, Folder 3)
      William Vaughn Moody Lecture.
    - University of Delaware, 1961 June 11 (Box 246, Folder 4)